Name- Sandeep

Mob. - +9609124281 & +91 9717564011

Whats App :- +91 9717564011

Skype – sandeep.powar4

Email: sandeeppowar90@gmail.com

Linkedin - https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandeep-powar-b2648b33

Add – House No. 654/25, Hansi, Haryana, India (125033)

#### **Professional Summary**

10+ years of IT & Telecommunication infrastructure experience in IT & Hospitality Industry in maintaining highest IT standards, preparing and advising on technology budget, project implementation, staff management, vendor relationship, supporting and troubleshooting diverse Property Management Systems (PMS), network administration, POS terminals, EPABX and host of Windows & proprietary OS.

Extensive knowledge of: Microsoft Windows Server 2003, 2008, 2012, Hyper-V & VMWare Workstation.

Microsoft Office 2007, 2010, 2013 & 2016 wired and wireless networking skills, desktop and server hardware and antivirus and remote support products & servers and computer peripherals & interfaces.

Small to medium-sized applications, acquired proficiency in maintaining mission-critical servers & processes, anti-virus & security policies, telecom & technology operations, office equipment's, documentation, providing training, etc. and fully conversant with hotel operations.

#### **Technical Skills:-**

- ❖ NETWORK & SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION.
- ❖ WINDOWS SERVER: 2003, 2008 & 2012.
- ❖ VIRTUAL SERVER HYPER V 6.2 & VMWARE WORKSTATION 14.
- **❖** MS-EXCHANGE SERVER: **2007**, **2013** & OFFICE 365.
- **MS-OFFICE: 2007, 2010 & 2013**
- **❖** MS-OUTLOOK: **2007**, **2010** & **2013**.
- **❖** OPERA PMS :- **5.5**
- **❖** MICROS POS: **3700**, **9700 & SIMPHONY**.
- ❖ OPERATING SYSTEMS: WINDOWS **XP**, **7**, **8** & **10**.
- ❖ FIREWALL'S: PRONTO, NOMADIX, 24 ONLINE, CYBEROAM, SOPHOS, FORTI GATE & INGATE.
- ❖ BACK OFFICE SOFTWARE SYSTEM: BOSS, PRISM, STAR, FAMS, SUN, PROLIFIC, MATERIALS CONTROL, CANSYS, CATS, EWIT, VING CARD, ONITY & CMS.
- **❖** UNIFI CONTROLLER :- **5.6.39**
- ❖ EPABX & PABX SYSTEM SERVER
- ❖ IPTV & IP PHONE
- ❖ ANTIVIRUS: SYMANTEC ENDPOINT PROTECTION.
- ❖ System Hardware & Networking
- NETWORK & PRINTER'S.
- ❖ SWITCHES & ROUTERS.
- ❖ DVR & NVR.
- ❖ GPON NETWORK.
- **❖** AUDIOVISUALS.
- Storage Management NAS & SAN
- **❖** BACKUP MANAGEMENT
- ❖ PROJECT MANAGEMENT.
- SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGEMENT.



### **Work History:-**

# <u>Courtyard by Marriott and Fairfield by Marriott Bengaluru, India.</u> Asst Multi-Property IT Manager 01 March 2022 to Till Date

# Job Summary:Handling the Entire IT Department as a Head of the Department

Supports the property's technology Information Resources objectives. Supports all technology Planning, decision-making, implementation, and maintenance. Interfaces with vendors, owners, and Property staff

- > Running regular checks on network and data security
- > Identifying and acting on opportunities to improve and update software and systems
- > Developing and implementing IT policy and best practice guides for the organisation
- > Designing training programs and workshops for staff
- > Conducting regular system audits
- > Running and sharing regular operation system reports with senior staff
- > Overseeing and determining timeframes for major IT projects including system updates, upgrades, migrations and outages
- > Managing and reporting on allocation of IT budget
- > Providing direction for IT team members
- > Identifying opportunities for team training and skills advancement
- > Own projects, solutions, and key responsibilities within a larger business initiative
- > Handle business-critical IT tasks and systems administration
- Research and evaluate emerging technologies, hardware, and software
- > Track and maintain hardware and software inventory

### Raffles Maldives Meradhoo, Maldives.

**SR IT Supervisor** 

**20 September 2019 to 28 February 2022** 

# Job Summary:-

#### Handling the IT Department alone from March 2020 to till,

As a member of the property management staff, contributes advanced knowledge and skill in Technology and general hospitality business knowledge to support the property and technology Information Resources objectives. Position is responsible to the property for all technology Planning, decision-making, implementation, and maintenance. May interfaces with vendors, Executive Committee and property staff.

- ➤ Uses computers and computer systems (including hardware and software) to program, write Software, set up functions, enter data, or process information.
- Assists in monitoring computer and network operations at the property, backup/recovery functions are performed on scheduled basis and administration functions for hardware, operating and application systems are maintained and completed on consistent basis.
- ➤ Monitors compliance with IR policies and standards protecting company hardware, software and other resources at the property.

- > Provides information to supervisors and co-workers by telephone, in written form, e-mail, or in person.
- ➤ Assists in vendor management for property IT requirements, functioning as escalation point for problem resolution.

# <u>Hulhule Island Hotel, Male, Maldives.</u> IT Executive

30 May 2017 to 20 June 2019.

#### JOB SUMMARY:-

### <u>Handling the Entire IT Department of Hulhule Island Hotel (HIH) Managed By</u> Singapore Airport Terminal Service Limited (SATS) as a Head of the Department.

Supports the property's technology Information Resources objectives. Supports all technology Planning, decision-making, implementation, and maintenance. Interfaces with vendors, owners, and Property staff.

- Monitor information collection and reporting systems and technology to ensure security, accessibility and accuracy of data in support of business processes and decision-making.
- ➤ Evaluate externally supplied programs/packages and recommend course of action; evaluate and maintain hardware and software to meet user requirements; assist in review of hardware and software contracts; foster shared use of technology among users.
- Assist with the development of automated workflows to support business processes.
- > Ensure user work stations function correctly on the network; administer an electronic mail system for all users; help to provide security administration and define the network environment.
- Draft analytical and technical specifications, reports, proposals, correspondence and presentations for various stakeholders; conduct studies; participate on project teams; and collaborate on special initiatives.
- > Contribute to external forums, professional discussions and initiatives to remain current regarding new trends and innovations in the field.

# Radisson Blu Plaza Delhi Mahipalpur & Radisson Blu Kaushambi Delhi NCR IT Supervisor 03 Sep 2012 to 23 May 2017.

## Job Summary:-Handling the IT Department as Second Command of department,

Troubleshoot and repair technical problems or issues related to computer hardware and peripheral Equipment. Respond to program error messages by finding and correcting problems or terminating The program. Provide technical guidance and recommendations to resolve business problems. Refer Major hardware/software problems or defective products to vendors or technicians for service. Enter Commands and activate controls on computer and peripheral equipment (e.g., printers) to integrate And operate equipment. Maintain and upgrade hardware and software, including peripherals (e.g. Printers, scanners) and website technical architecture related to hardware and telecommunication Connectivity.

- > Supporting and assisting the IT Operations Regional Team in Mainz, ensuring the highest levels of service are provided to guests and team members.
- > Supporting the Director of IT and General Manager as and when required, to ensure the Hotel is technologically advanced and efficient with all matters relating to hospitality IT.
- Taking ownership for the efficient operation and maintenance of all computer systems and data communications activities in the hotel.

- In general, taking control of SW and HW used by the hotel (Maintaining PCs, printers, telephones and credit card terminals, among others).
- Assist in the preparation of any ad-hoc analysis, reports or services as requested by Corporate Office or the Senior Hotel Management.
- Answer users IT related enquiries and provide assistance when necessary.
- > Having a thorough understanding of server and overall network maintenance.

# Tata Communication Internet Service Ltd Pay roll of Randstad India. Cyber Executive 23 Nov 2011 to 31 Oct 2012

#### **Job Summary:-**

## Handling the Entire IT Department Network and ISP of Radisson Delhi

- Establish the networking environment by designing system configuration, directing system installation and defining, documenting and enforcing system standards.
- Maximize network performance by monitoring performance, troubleshooting network problems and outages, scheduling upgrades and collaborating with network architects on network optimization.
- Undertake data network fault investigations in local and wide area environments using information from multiple sources.
- > Design and implement new solutions and improve resilience of the current environment.
- Configure routing and switching equipment services and firewalls.

Successful Pre-Opening of Lebua Hotel New Delhi.
Pay Roll of Airlink Wireless System Pvt Ltd
Resident Engineer

25Jan2011 to 19 Dec 2011

#### **Job Summary:-**

- Establish the networking environment by designing system configuration, directing system installation and defining, documenting and enforcing system standards.
- > Design and implement new solutions and improve resilience of the current environment.
- Support and administer firewall environments in line with IT security policy.
- Upgrade data network equipment to the latest stable firmware releases.
- > Undertake capacity management and audit of IP addressing and hosted devices.

#### **Education**

August 2007- July 2010 Passed Computer Engineering From Government Polytechnic College Uttawar (Palwal) Harvana, India

July 2003– August 2005 Passed Electronic's from Government Industrial Training Insistitute

Hisar, Haryana, India

•

I do, hereby declare that the above-furnished details are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Date

Place (Sandeep)